# **Thomas Seropian**

French nationality, Indefinite leave to remain Currently based in London, United Kingdom thomas@seropian.io https://uk.linkedin.com/in/tseropian

# **Tech Lead / Software Architect**

# Profile

A team leader and Software Engineer with a 14 years track record in delivery and innovation across several tech companies and startups. I help organisations to apply new ranges of technologies to solve challenging real-world problems, and ultimately to build and launch successful products that customers love.

I act as a bridge or liaison between the engineering team and the rest of the business, with a strong hands-on technical element (to stay relevant to the Engineering effort) and management responsibility (to have the authority to get stuff done). Essentially, I like to lead software development and delivery on technically interesting projects.

Skill set: building web applications, leading technical teams. System designing. Leadership, communication with technical and non-technical audiences. Strong sense of innovation. Design and creation of user stories. Research, prototyping. Flexibility. Project management. Hiring, mentoring and performance management.es

## Work experience

Senior/Lead Full Stack Engineer (contract based) for a software consultancy AND Digital, London, United Kingdom – July 2019 to present (<a href="www.and.digital">www.and.digital</a>)

ightarrow Working on a cloud transformation project for a nationwide insurance client.

Scoping new requirements for an end-user web application and the related REST backend services. Writing code following test-driven development. Delivering new features. Managing integration with 3rd party back-office services (both REST and SOAP). Code reviews across all teams. Agile (SCRUM) delivery.

→ <u>Technology:</u> Serverless, Javascript, ES6, Express, Node.js, React, Docker, Kubernetes, Azure, REST, SOAP.

# **Lead Software Engineer / Head of Engineering** for a med-tech startup **Skin Analytics,** London, United Kingdom – October 2017 to May 2019 (www.skin-analytics.com)

→ Responsible for clients, internal and commercial applications and infrastructures

Managing applications and cloud infrastructure (AWS), including release processes and improvements.

Designing, defining roadmaps, scoping new requirements. Writing code. Hiring and leading technical team (both in house and contractors), day to day management, code reviews and testing with a focus on security. Leading design and delivery of a commercial Software as a Medical Device (IEC 62304) cloud-based API.

→ <u>Technology:</u> AWS, Node.js, Angular 7, TypeScript, React, React Native, MySQL, MongoDB, Docker, Ansible.

#### Mentor and Advisor, since 2018

- → Mentoring for the tech lead curriculum for the main french online education platform Open Classrooms
- → Coach and advisor for a startup challenge about Blockchain and social impact

**Technical Lead (contract based)** for an international online media publishing group **Jamie Oliver,** London, United Kingdom – February to September 2017 (www.jamieoliver.com)

- → Responsible for infrastructure and web applications supporting Jamie's online presence.

  Scoping migration from a legacy SOAP CRM system. Designing and delivering a micro service driven brand new CRM pipeline. Managing contractors. Managing AWS infrastructure, release processes and optimisations.
- → <u>Technology:</u> AWS, Node.js, TypeScript, PHP (Laravel), RESTful APIs, Redis, Solr, Vue.js, WordPress, Varnish.

### **Technology / Team leader** for an international NGO

Internews London, United Kingdom – April 2015 to December 2016 (www.internews.org)

- → Leading the design, development, and delivery of innovation and technology components

  Working with a multidisciplinary team supporting local start-ups among the most repressive regimes.

  Leading on delivering news publishing apps. Managing activities' budgets. Speaking at conferences and events.
- → Managing technology team and resources across multiple projects (8 countries)

  Overseeing the recruitment and day-to-day managing a team of 4 technologists. Ensuring planning, setting priorities, agreeing on detailed work plans, budgets, and schedules. Coaching and mentoring team members. Agile delivery. Responsible for technical architecture and roadmap. Focus on scalability & security.
- → <u>Technology:</u> Node.js, PHP (Laravel), Wordpress, Drupal (7/8), Ansible, Nginx, OpenVPN, encryption. **ICT Projects Manager / Web Application Engineer** for an international NGO **Internews** Paris, France / London, United Kingdom March 2009 to March 2015 (www.internews.org)
- → Online freedom of expression, support of local media, digital security

  Designing, developing & supporting multilingual web applications, custom modules. Integration with social network (Twitter, Facebook) APIs. Writing documentation for users. Managing localization, training & support. Writing user stories & specifications. Managing external contractors and developers, resources & infrastructures: Deployment and monitoring of servers, secure hosting & video platforms. Building & delivering and facilitating training & trainers on ICT topics. Training of trainers on website building and digital security (West Africa, MENA).
- → <u>Technology</u>: Drupal, Mediawiki, XML/JSON, PHP (OOP, MVC), MySQL, Solr, AWS, Collectd, Vagrant, Nginx.

**Software Engineer** for a social networking service designed for a family use **Hellotipi.com** Paris, France – February 2008 to January 2009 (www.hellotipi.com)

- $\rightarrow$  Designed, developed and implemented new features for the service. Video sharing. Photo tagging. Revamped the registration process. Multilingual support. Managed client support.
- → <u>Technology</u>: Debian, Apache, MySQL, PHP5 (OOP, MVC), XML, Jquery, Ffmpeg.

ICT Projects Manager for a local NGO in Armenia

Fondation KASA Yerevan, Armenia - March 2006 to September 2007 (www.kasa.am)

Coordinated Computer training in youth training centres. Developed activities in the 2 major cities. Managed the recruitment of the local team. Provided technical support for training & social programs. Participated in feasibility studies & design for countrywide projects.

**Assistant Projects Manager** for e-training IT projects for an international training centre **Valeo Thermal Systems** Paris, France – March 2005 to February 2006 (www.valeo.com) Designed & implemented tools for course supports creation (virtual classes, e-learning modules).

#### Education

## **MSc in Computer Sciences and Innovation**

Ecole Supérieure d'Informatique, Electronique, Automatique Paris, France

5 years engineering school in information technologies & electronics (www.esiea.fr).

 $\rightarrow$  Graduated with first class honours.

## Foreign languages

French: Mother tongue English: Fluent Spanish: Basic level Arabic: Beginner